Susan Bakay

◆131 Providence Forge, Royersford, PA 19468 ◆ 610-812-8147 ◆ susan.bakay@comcast.net◆

'It is my opinion that

Susan will be a positive

force on any faculty. She

will be a team player....she

truly cares about her

profession, but most of all

she cares about children."

Greg McCord Supervisor

"She demonstrated

leadership and initiative

and has the ability to task

analyze context and teach it

in a step-by-step manner,

always diagnosing and

evaluating evidence of

student learning along the

way....She is a true

asset..."

Devon Wisler 3rd grade teacher

Professional Profile

Eager to obtain an upper elementary or middle grades teaching position and use a unique combination of education, experience and commitment to motivate and engage students.

- Committed to inclusive, multicultural education and motivated to provide differentiated instruction in all lessons for the benefit of all students.
- Experienced with differentiated instruction, a variety of classroom management techniques, and creating a positive learning environment.

Certifications and Education

Certifications

PA State Reading Specialist (K-12).

PA State Elementary Education (K-6th).

PA State Middle Grades English (7-9).

Education

M.Ed. Multicultural Education (4.0) Eastern University, St. David's, PA. May 2014

Bachelor of Arts, Literature

West Chester University, West Chester, PA. 1991

Key Qualifications

Certified in Elementary (K-6) and Middle Grades English (7-9). Reading Specialist Certification(K-12).

Plan and instruct using wide variety of teaching aids, motivational and implementation strategies to engage students in active learning.

Demonstrated ability to implement data in instructional planning and delivery.

Implement remedial strategies effectively and for individual or group instruction.

Develop and maintain consistent and effective classroom management techniques for maximum student time on task.

Utilize differentiated instruction to support all learners. Able to quickly adjust teaching for a variety of learning styles and to provide scaffolding.

Related Experience

Write, plan and adapt instruction and curriculum for multi-cultural groups. Teach as a lead teacher, in teams and co-teaching situations. Provide support to special needs students in inclusive classrooms. Involve students in a variety of experiences to inspire a desire to learn. Motivate and engage students with differing cultural backgrounds to produce tangible, positive results for all. Support and conference with students and parents. Team-oriented and flexible with schedules and adapting to school and student needs. Experience with hearing impaired learners, autistic spectrum students, and dyslexic and hyperlexic learners and intellectually disabled students.

"Susan actively engages the students, makes provisions for individual differences

and promotes student

cooperation, responsibility

and leadership."

Dr. Michelle Cinciripino, Principal

'Her presence and her

considerable gifts would

strengthen and be an

incalculable blessing to any

community with whom she

works."

Martin Rolfs-Massaglia former supervisor

Special Skills & Activities

- Lindamood-Bell Learning Processes experience with research and techniques and Wilson Fundations experience.
- LETRS training
- Published in *International Journal of Multicultural Education* author and book reviewer for children's and young adult literature
- Computer: Experienced with 3M, SmartBoard and Promethian board technology. Skilled in Microsoft Word, Powerpoint, Excel, Access, One Note and Outlook, use of Study Island for student practice and assessment, use of internet, Reading Eggs, TenMarks, Adobe Photoshop and other applications.
- Drama and the Arts: Directed, produced and managed stage productions for children and youth, utilized music and art in learning situations.
- A/V Technology: Excellent flexibility with a variety of technologies including regular use of digital video and photo, document cameras, Smartboards, lighting, sound equipment and computers.
- Community Service: Transformational instruction utilizing community awareness and experience. Designed and implemented children and youth focused educational service programs for awareness of issues related to poverty. Led groups of children and youth to serve in local shelters, food pantries, thrift stores, construction work and etc.

Employment

- Pottstown School District, September 2013 to present Classroom Assistant, Elizabeth B. Barth Elementary, Stowe, PA
- Lindamood-Bell Learning Processes, May 2013 to Aug. 2013
 Clinician working with three LB programs, Bryn Mawr, PA
- Spring-Ford Area School District, October 2012 to January 2014
 District Substitute Teacher, Various grades, Royersford, PA
- Chester County Intermediate Unit, August 2012 to October 2013
 Substitute Teacher, Various grades and schools, Downingtown, PA
- Substitute Teacher Service, June 2012 to October 2013
 Substitute Teacher, Various grades and schools, Aston, PA
- Student Teacher, January to May 2012
 Third grade, South Elementary, Collegeville, PA
- Coordinator of Youth Ministry, June 2003 to August 2012
 First grade through College levels. Responsible for all facets of programming including curriculum, education and staffing.
 Royersford Baptist Church, Royersford PA

Professional Affiliations

National Council of Teachers of English International Reading Association Association for Middle Level Education